Guide to the Washington Dearmont Papers, 1787-1944 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Washington Dearmont papers 1787-1944 and undated, bulk 1851-1930
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Dearmont, Washington
5.0 linear feet Extent: Approximately 5200 Items
Farmer and salt agent, of Clarke Co., Va. Routine family and business correspondence, some of it relating to Dearmont’s position as a salt agent. A few Civil War letters contain orders preparatory to the march on Harper’s Ferry and concern the procurement of salt and horses. Later correspondence concerns Mamie Dearmont and relates in part to women in politics in Colorado, 1912. Other topics of correspondence include Virginia politics, and school life at Eastern College, Front Royal, Va., and at the Medical College of Virginia in Richmond. There are also business records of the following persons: George Weaver, a merchant at White Post; Greenbury W. Weaver; the postmaster at White Post; G. C. Hamill; and William Berry of Clarke County. The earliest dates refer to financial ledgers and other volumes; one of these contains ledgers of G. C. Hamill and of Washington Dearmont.
RL.00319
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Washington Dearmont Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1957.
Collection Overview
Routine family and business correspondence dating from 1787 to 1944, with the bulk of the collection dating from 1851-1930. A portion of the records relate to Dearmont’s position as a salt agent. A few Civil War letters contain orders preparatory to the march on Harper’s Ferry and concern the procurement of salt and horses. Later correspondence concerns Mamie Dearmont and relates in part to women in politics in Colorado, 1912. Other topics of correspondence include Virginia politics, and school life at Eastern College, Front Royal, Va., and at the Medical College of Virginia in Richmond. There are also business records of the following persons: George Weaver, a merchant at White Post; Greenbury W. Weaver; the postmaster at White Post; G. C. Hamill; and William Berry of Clarke County. The earliest dates refer to financial ledgers and other volumes; one of these contains ledgers of G. C. Hamill and of Washington Dearmont.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Berry, William; Dearmont family; Dearmont, Mamie; Dearmont, Washington; Hammill, G. C.; Weaver, George; Weaver, Greeenbury W.; Confederate States of America. Army -- Supplies and stores; Eastern College (Front Royal, Va.)--Students; Medical College of Virginia -- Students; Education -- Virginia; Medical education -- Virginia; Merchants -- Virginia -- White Post; Postmasters -- United States; Salt industry and trade -- Confederate States of America; Salt industry and trade -- Virginia; Women in politics -- Colorado; Harpers Ferry (W. Va.)--History -- John Brown’s Raid, 1859; White Post (Va.)--Commerce
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence Series, 1845-1938 and undated, (1.5 boxes)
  - 1845-1904 (Box 1)
  - 1905-1938 and undated (Box 2)
- Legal Papers Series, 1815-1944 and undated, (1.5 boxes)
  - 1815-1850 (Box 2)
  - 1850-1944 and undated (Box 3)
- Financial Papers Series, 1809-1930 and undated, (4.5 boxes)
  - 1809-1840 (Box 3)
  - 1840-1850 (Box 4)
  - 1850-1860 (Box 5)
  - Undated financial papers; clippings, printed material, and other items (Box 6)
  - 1860-1930 (Box 10)
- Volumes Series, (3 boxes)
  - Boxed volumes (Box 7-9)
  - Fourteen other manuscript volumes are shelved onsite; please consult the online catalog for locations.